Kate Braid fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- CBC Ideas - Men of the Deep, 1991-1994; F-10-12; 14 cm of textual records 26 sound recordings on 27 audio cassettes
  - Transcript of concert, intermission and after, 1992; F-10-12-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-30)
  - Men of the Deep research and background. Information on Westray Mines., 1991-1992; F-10-12-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-30)
  - Men of the Deep research and background. Information on Westray Mines., 1991-1992; F-10-12-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 10-30)
- Appointment calendars, 1985-2009; F-10-13; 24 cm of textual records.
  Series consists of appointment calendars kept by Braid. The calendars document meetings with colleagues, friends, family, medical and other appointments, and other day-to-day events.
  - Appointment calendars, 1985-1986; F-10-13-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-35)
  - Appointment calendars, 1987-1990; F-10-13-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - Appointment calendars, 1991; F-10-13-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - Appointment calendars, 1991-1994; F-10-13-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - Appointment calendars, 1994; F-10-13-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - Appointment calendars, 1995; F-10-13-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - Appointment calendars, 1996-1997; F-10-13-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - Appointment calendars, 1996-1997; F-10-13-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-37)
  - Appointment calendars, 1996-1997; F-10-13-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-37)
  - Book of quotations, 1970; F-10-13-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-37)
  - Appointment calendars, 2005-2006; F-10-13-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-60)
  - Appointment calendars, 2007-2008; F-10-13-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-60)
  - Appointment calendars, 2009-2012; F-10-13-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-60)
- Correspondence, 1970-2013; F-10-14; 1.34 m of textual records 1 photograph
  Series consists of correspondence, both letters and electronic mail (printed out) of Braid's vast and wide-ranging volume of communication with colleagues, publishers, editors, fellow writers, friends, family, and lovers. Series is arranged in 3 subseries: Business correspondence, Correspondence with writers, and Personal correspondence. After 2006 the Personal correspondence subseries also contains correspondence with writers.
  - Business correspondence, 1990-2010; F-10-14-1; 24 cm of textual records
    Subseries includes correspondence with editors, publishers, bookstores, as well as invoices, and other administrative records, primarily relating to submitting poems, articles, or other writing for publication but also applications for grants and honoraria for poetry readings.
    - Correspondence - business, 1990-1993; F-10-14-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-37)
    - Correspondence - business, 1990-1993; F-10-14-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-37)
    - Correspondence - business, 1998-1999; F-10-14-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-37)
    - Correspondence - business, 1999-2001; F-10-14-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-37)
    - Correspondence - business, 1999-2001; F-10-14-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-38)
    - Correspondence - business, 2001-2003; F-10-14-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-44)
    - Correspondence - business, 2001-2003; F-10-14-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-44)
    - Correspondence - business, 2004-2006; F-10-14-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-44)
    - Correspondence - business, 2004-2006; F-10-14-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-44)
    - Correspondence - business, 2006-2009; F-10-14-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-45)
    - Correspondence - business, 2006-2009; F-10-14-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-45)
    - Correspondence - business - SFU Labour program brochure, 1994-1995; F-10-14-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-45)
    - Correspondence - business, 2009-2010; F-10-14-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-45)
  - Correspondence with writers, 1992-2006; F-10-14-2; 34 cm of textual records
    Series consists of letters and emails with fellow writers regarding a wide variety of writing-related issues, including reviewing others poems and having her poems reviewed. Correspondents include George McWhirter, Joy Kogawa, PK Page, Lynne Bowen, Patrick Lane, Lorna Crozier, Sandy Shreve, and a host of other fellow poets and mentors.
    - Correspondence with writers, 1992-1996; F-10-14-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1992-1996; F-10-14-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1992-1996; F-10-14-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1993-1999; F-10-14-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1997-1998; F-10-14-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1997-1998; F-10-14-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1998-1999; F-10-14-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1998-1999; F-10-14-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1999-2000; F-10-14-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1999-2000; F-10-14-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-39)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1999; F-10-14-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-40)
    - Correspondence with writers, 1999; F-10-14-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-40)
    - Correspondence with writers, 2000-2001; F-10-14-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-43)
    - Correspondence with writers, 2001-2004; F-10-14-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-43)
    - Correspondence with writers, 2001-2004; F-10-14-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-43)
    - Correspondence with writers, 2005-2006; F-10-14-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 10-43)
    - Correspondence with writers, 2005-2006; F-10-14-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 10-44)
  - Personal correspondence, 1970-2013; F-10-14-3; 74 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of personal correspondence with Braid's parents, siblings, friends and former lovers. In about 2006 the subseries also includes correspondence with fellow writers.
    This subseries is restricted until December 31, 2025. Access is granted only by permission of the donor.
    - Correspondence - personal, 2002-2008; F-10-14-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-45)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2002-2008; F-10-14-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-45)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2007-2008; F-10-14-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2007-2008; F-10-14-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2008; F-10-14-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2008; F-10-14-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2009; F-10-14-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2009; F-10-14-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2009; F-10-14-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2009-2010; F-10-14-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2009-2010; F-10-14-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 1971; F-10-14-3-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-54)
    - Correspondence - personal - Malaspina, 2003-2004; F-10-14-3-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-47)
    - Correspondence - personal, 1976; F-10-14-3-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-54)
    - Correspondence - personal, 1978-1980; F-10-14-3-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-54)
    - Correspondence - personal, 1971-1974; F-10-14-3-0-16 (Archival box - standard 10-54)
    - Correspondence - personal, 1970-1975; F-10-14-3-0-17 (Archival box - standard 10-54)
    - Correspondence - personal, 1976-1977; F-10-14-3-0-18 (Archival box - standard 10-54)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2010; F-10-14-3-0-19 (Archival box - standard 10-56)
    - Correspondence - personal - letters from Peter Sarsfield, 2010; F-10-14-3-0-20 (Archival box - standard 10-54)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2010; F-10-14-3-0-21 (Archival box - standard 10-56)
    - Correspondence - personal - January - June, 2010; F-10-14-3-0-22 (Archival box - standard 10-57)
    - Correspondence - personal - July - December, 2010; F-10-14-3-0-23 (Archival box - standard 10-56)
    - Correspondence - personal - July - December, 2010; F-10-14-3-0-24 (Archival box - standard 10-56)
    - Correspondence - personal, 1995-2008; F-10-14-3-0-25 (Archival box - standard 10-57)
    - Correspondence - personal, 1995-2008; F-10-14-3-0-26 (Archival box - standard 10-57)
    - Correspondence - personal - "Uppers" letters of appreciation, 2003-2008; F-10-14-3-0-27 (Archival box - standard 10-57)
    - Malaspina college - students, 2002-2008; F-10-14-3-0-28 (Archival box - standard 10-57)
    - Malaspina grants, 2003-2008; F-10-14-3-0-29 (Archival box - standard 10-57)
    - Correspondence - personal - applications for grants, 1997-2006; F-10-14-3-0-30 (Archival box - standard 10-57)
    - Correspondence - personal - Jan to Jun 2011, F-10-14-3-0-31 (Archival box - standard 10-72)
    - Correspondence - personal - Jan to Jun 2011, 2012; F-10-14-3-0-32 (Archival box - standard 10-72)
    - Correspondence - personal - July to December 2011, 2013; F-10-14-3-0-33 (Archival box - standard 10-72)
    - Correspondence - personal - July to December 2011, 2013; F-10-14-3-0-34 (Archival box - standard 10-72)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2012; F-10-14-3-0-35 (Archival box - standard 10-73)
    - Correspondence - personal, 2010; F-10-14-3-0-36 (Archival box - standard 10-73)
    - Correspondence - personal - July to Dec 2012, 2010; F-10-14-3-0-37 (Archival box - standard 10-73)
- Personal and early accomplishments, 1965-1967; F-10-15; 6 cm of textual records 1 photograph
  Series consists of Braid's valedictory address at Mt. Allison University in 1967, her graduation photograph, ad old passports.
  - Kate Braid - valedictory address, 1967; F-10-15-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-49)
  - Kate Braid - graduation photograph, 1967; F-10-15-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-59)
  - Passports, 1965-1999; F-10-15-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-60)
- Writing and teaching projects, 1974-2010; F-10-16; 1.10 m of textual records 21 sound recordings on 25 audio cassettes 2 moving images on 2 videocassettes
  Series consists of records relating to many different writing projects in which Braid was involved, including Poetry in Transit, Poetry Train, Prosody group, Sex Death and Madness writing group, League of Canadian poets, The Fish Come in Dancing, CBC Ideas, Victoria School of Writing, and the Vancouver Industrial Writers Union, among other projects.
  - SFU Women's studies 307 creative non-fiction interviews, 2006; F-10-16-1; 15 sound recordings on 18 audio cassettes
    Subseries consists of interviews for an SFU women's studies course on creative non-fiction taught by Braid in 2006.
    Restricted in whole due to the fragile nature of the medium. Access only after digitization.
    - Mrs. Kask (cannery worker) "A woman's work" interviewed by Joy Berkana, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-1; 1 audio cassette 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-4778)
      - OBJ-4778_sideA.wav
      - OBJ-4778_sideB.wav
    - Manisha Dadlani (social worker) interviewed by Emily Reskovich, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-2 (Audio cassette OBJ-4779)
    - Anne Ironside "Feminist adult education and the WRC" interviewed by Nikkki Scott, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-3 (Audio cassette OBJ-4780)
    - Val Fawkes interviewed by Jessica Au, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-4781)
    - Val Fawkes interviewed by Jessica Au, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-4782)
    - Frances Stathay (lawyer) interviewed by Peggy Tisdale, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-6 (Audio cassette OBJ-4783)
    - Josephine Olivia Harrison interviewed by Kristal van Leeuwen, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-7 (Audio cassette OBJ-4784)
    - Josephine Olivia Harrison interviewed by Kristal van Leeuwen, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-8 (Audio cassette OBJ-4785)
    - Mary Jane Lucas (elementary school teacher / principal) interviewed by Erin Taylor, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-9 (Audio cassette OBJ-4786)
    - Julie Kathleen Nelson interviewed by Kim Tang, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-10 (Audio cassette OBJ-4787)
    - Gail Jarvis (teacher) interviewed by Leanne MacLean, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-11 (Audio cassette OBJ-4788)
    - Lesma Allen interviewed by Leonie Uwimana, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-12 (Audio cassette OBJ-4789)
    - Sharon Collins interviewed by Jessica Wright, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-13 (Audio cassette OBJ-4790)
    - Annie Hawk Johnson (elder, Cree nation) interviewed by Lee-Ann Lalli, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-14 (Audio cassette OBJ-4791)
    - Annie Hawk Johnson (elder, Cree nation) interviewed by Lee-Ann Lalli, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-15 (Audio cassette OBJ-4792)
    - Susan Boxer interviewed by Cindy Allan, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-16 (Audio cassette OBJ-4793)
    - Vera Nordstrom (teacher) interviewed by Mallory Johnson, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-17 (Audio cassette OBJ-4794)
    - Kathleen Lindstrom (doula prenatal care) interviewed by Amanda Emsley, 2006; F-10-16-1-0-18 (Audio cassette OBJ-4795)
  - CBC Writers & Co Eleanor Wachtel, 2002; F-10-16-0-0-0-1; 1 sound recording (Audio cassette OBJ-4798)
  - Recollections of unknown subject regarding her experiences in the north, including the Arctic and Northwest Territories, ca 1980; F-10-16-0-0-0-2; 1 sound recording (Audio cassette OBJ-4799)
  - "Duende" Sex Death Madness (SDM) writer's group recording of group discussion with Sheila Norgate, Tana Runyan, Cynthia Flood, Thuong Riddick, Sandy Shreve, Kate Brai, ca. 1998; F-10-16-0-0-0-3; 1 sound recording on 1 audio cassette (Audio cassette OBJ-4730)
  - Split shift: songs and poems of the workplace (Fraser Union with the Vancouver Industrial Writers' Union), 1989; F-10-16-0-0-0-4 (Audio cassette OBJ-4800)
  - Kate Braid being interviewed by CBC Radio July 24 1992 and Dec 2, 1996, 1992-1996; F-10-16-0-0-0-5 (Audio cassette OBJ-4801)
  - Kate Braid interview, 2000; F-10-16-0-0-0-6; 1 videocassette 1 .mov file (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4806)
    - OBJ-4806-dgt.mov
  - Blue Moon Reading Abbotsford Kate Braid and friends, 2008; F-10-16-0-0-0-7; 1 videocassette 2 .mkv files (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-4807)
    .mkv files also available in .mp4 format.
    Pending review
    - OBJ-4807-dgt_pt1.mkv
    - OBJ-4807-dgt_pt2.mkv
  - Essays and speeches, 1986-2003; F-10-16-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-35)
  - The writers union of Canada - counting men vs women publications, 1997-1998; F-10-16-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-35)
  - Technical university interim planning council, 1995-1996; F-10-16-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-35)
  - Dorothy Livesay paper, 2000-2001; F-10-16-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-35)
  - Poetry in Transit committee - BC Book Publisher's Association, 1999-2000; F-10-16-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - League of Canadian poets listserv, 1994-1998; F-10-16-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - The writers union of Canada and BC Ferries Corporation, 2000-2001; F-10-16-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - Address book and accounts book, 1984-1988; F-10-16-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - Prosody group, 1999-2001; F-10-16-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - Sex, Death, and Madness in Vancouver writers group. First draft, 2008; F-10-16-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - 1997 Audit, 1995-1997; F-10-16-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-36)
  - The Fish Come in Dancing (edited by Braid) project file, 2002; F-10-16-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-40)
  - Writers in electronic residence, 1997-2000; F-10-16-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-40)
  - Labour Canada Women's Bureau - "Building the future", 1988-1989; F-10-16-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-40)
  - Author reading flyers and ads, 1992-1996; F-10-16-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-40)
  - Betsy Warland benefit, 2001; F-10-16-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 10-40)
  - CBC Ideas, 1989, 1991 Women in the Trades and Men of the Deeps, F-10-16-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 10-40)
  - CBC Ideas - A Journey of Women - women in trades, work notes, interview notes, 1990-1992; F-10-16-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 10-41)
  - Victoria School of Writing, 2003; F-10-16-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 10-41)
  - On the Poetry Train (correspondence and records regarding participating in a poetry series on Via Rail train), 2003; F-10-16-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 10-42)
  - Translating Canadian women's poetry into Spanish (Mexico), 1999-2006; F-10-16-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 10-48)
  - Island highway project 'the road to equity', 2000; F-10-16-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 10-48)
  - Letter from Tom Wayman, 1999; F-10-16-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 10-48)
  - WCB / Sexual harassment, 1997-2008; F-10-16-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 10-48)
  - Women in trades and technology - Women building futures - Judy Lynn Archer, 2007; F-10-16-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 10-48)
  - Senior women oral histories (from undergraduate course Braid taught), 2006; F-10-16-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 10-48)
  - Sex death and madness (SDM) writer's group, 1995-2008; F-10-16-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 10-48)
  - Robin Blaser's notes SFU English 803, 1974-1975; F-10-16-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 10-48)
  - Vancouver industrial writers union, 1986-1993; F-10-16-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 10-49)
  - Vancouver industrial writers union, 1986-1993; F-10-16-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 10-49)
  - Vancouver industrial writers union accounts and organizational documents, 1987-1992; F-10-16-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 10-49)
  - Mayworks labour festival, 1987-1988; F-10-16-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 10-49)
  - Papers relating to occupational choices, travel, 1984; F-10-16-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 10-55)
  - Operation solidarity, 1983; F-10-16-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 10-55)
  - Essays for SFU courses, 1975-1977; F-10-16-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 10-55)
  - "My parents file" - contains clippings, promotional materials about Braid, 1996-2007; F-10-16-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 10-55)
  - Braid family reunion, 1985; F-10-16-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 10-57)
  - Buttons with slogans, 1990; F-10-16-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 10-57)
  - BCIT Equity report, 1991; F-10-16-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - CBC ideas - proposal, 1994-1995; F-10-16-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - Memoristas, 2008-2010; F-10-16-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - Nanaimo poetry fringe festival, 1999-2001; F-10-16-0-0-42 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - Remarkable Women, 2012; F-10-16-0-0-43 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - Sex death and madness (SDM) writer's group, 1996-2008; F-10-16-0-0-44 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - SFU - appointments and products of her work, 1991-2007; F-10-16-0-0-45 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - SFU - Women's studies 307 - creative non-fiction, 2006; F-10-16-0-0-46 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - Teaching ephemera, 2007; F-10-16-0-0-47 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - Teaching evaluations - SFU - UBC - Malaspina, 1999-2002; F-10-16-0-0-48 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - UBC, 1997-2004; F-10-16-0-0-49 (Archival box - standard 10-58)
  - Articles and publicatons with Braid's poetry, 1990-1995; F-10-16-0-0-50 (Archival box - standard 10-59)
  - Collections of poetry, 2000; F-10-16-0-0-51 (Archival box - standard 10-59)
  - SFU Essays, 1976-1977; F-10-16-0-0-52 (Archival box - standard 10-59)
  - Women in trade publications, 1979-1997; F-10-16-0-0-53 (Archival box - standard 10-59)
  - Women in trade publications, 1979-1997; F-10-16-0-0-54 (Archival box - standard 10-59)
- Turning left to the ladies, 1990-2009; F-10-17; 12 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to Braid's work on her book Turning Left to the Ladies. Records include drafts, correspondence with her publisher and editor, and drafts for the editor.
  - Turning left to the ladies - drafts, 1990-2009; F-10-17-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-41)
  - Turning left to the ladies (publication) - signed by Braid, 2009; F-10-17-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-41)
  - Turning left to the ladies (TLL) correspondence with publisher and editor (Palimpsest), 2007-2009; F-10-17-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-51)
  - Turning left to the ladies (TLL) drafts, 2007-2009; F-10-17-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-51)
  - Turning left to the ladies (TLL) - draft for editor, 2009; F-10-17-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-51)
  - Turning left to the ladies (TLL) - draft for editor, 2009; F-10-17-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-51)
- Journeywoman, 1975-2012; F-10-18; 34 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to Kate's prose memoir Journeywoman. The non-fiction account was originally conceived as a novel (featuring a carpenter named Kelly) but over the years evolved into a memoir. Records include drafts of the novel, drafts of the memoir, early edits, notes, and correspondence.
  - Journeywoman (novel) 1995, F-10-18-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-51)
  - Journeywoman (novel) 1995, F-10-18-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-51)
  - Journeywoman (novel) draft to Helen Clark, 1992; F-10-18-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-52)
  - Journeywoman (novel) draft to Helen Clark, 1992; F-10-18-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-52)
  - Journeywoman (novel) notes, 1995; F-10-18-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-52)
  - Journeywoman - early editors, 2000-2012; F-10-18-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-52)
  - Journeywoman book notes, 1975-2012; F-10-18-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-52)
  - Journeywoman edit, 2012; F-10-18-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-53)
  - Journeywoman draft 9 Barbara Pulley's edits, 2012; F-10-18-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-53)
  - Journeywoman draft 9 Barbara Pulley's edits, 2012; F-10-18-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-53)
  - Journeywoman Barbara Pulley's final edit, 2012; F-10-18-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-53)
  - Journeywoman Barbara Pulley's final edit, 2012; F-10-18-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-53)
  - Journeywoman - various notes and correspondence, 1983-2011; F-10-18-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-53)
  - Journeywoman - Betsy Warland edit draft 4, 2011; F-10-18-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-50)
  - Journeywoman notes, 1993-2012; F-10-18-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-50)
  - Journeywoman - a carpenter's memoir draft 2, 2003; F-10-18-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 10-50)
  - Journeywoman - a carpenter's memoir draft 2, 2003; F-10-18-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 10-50)
- Diaries, 1963-2012; F-10-19; 1.08 m of textual records
  Series consists of daily diaries, notebooks, dream diaries, and travel diaries kept by Braid over a period of nearly 50 years. The diaries capture her reflections on various events in her life and in the world, the progress of her writing, and relationships with her family, friends, and others.
  This series is restricted until December 31, 2025. Access is granted only by permission of the donor.
  - Journal 2A - Kate's audio diary of her trip to London, [1990]; F-10-19-0-0-0-1 (Cassette box OBJ-4802)
  - Diaries - notebooks, 2010; F-10-19-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-55)
  - Diary, 1963-1967; F-10-19-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-61)
  - Diary, 1965-1967; F-10-19-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-61)
  - Diary - Travel diary - Canada-Chile world university service Canada, 1965; F-10-19-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-60)
  - Diary - travel diary - Europe, 1967; F-10-19-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-61)
  - Diary, 1971; F-10-19-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-62)
  - Diary, 1974; F-10-19-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-62)
  - Diary, 1977; F-10-19-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-62)